You know what I've noticed? I've noticed Gaza being described as an open-air prison or a concentration camp and
I don't agree with either of those terms and let me explain why. An open-air prison implies that they've done something wrong
when in fact
It's the opposite side
Ethnically cleansing, oppressing, and abusing them
Concentration camp is essentially a derivative from what Indian reservations were to the indigenous peoples of America
So I'm gonna call it like it is. It's a reservation
and I'll
the very
very similar parallels between indigenous peoples of the Americas and Palestinians is
Is a lot deeper than one might seem
because essentially the reservation system was created in the United States and not only track and
monitor the indigenous peoples
But also subjugate them further since outright genocide
wasn't as seen as
popular so they essentially
Invented new ways so that they could silently oppress silently genocide and silently unalive
the remaining indigenous peoples and
What's been going on with Gaza is that you don't exist if you don't have a registry to the state
If you don't register with military or health agencies that are affiliated with the state
And that's exactly what they did with indigenous peoples if you didn't have a card if you weren't logged with the Indian agent
If you weren't logged at all, you didn't exist as an indigenous person
Same thing with food sources. They would take those food sources away
that way you could be reliant on the state because
One of the things to diminish a people is if you take away their food sovereignty and their agriculture
Then you make them reliant on the state and you can control them. You can control their diets. Therefore you can control their health
especially with the surveillance and monitoring as well as the militarization and
Dehumanization is parallel to none
When it comes to indigenous peoples and Palestinians
Because you have the state actively
Dehumanizing you calling you an animal calling you a savage all the while monitoring and spying on you
Just for no reason and the same thing the same technology that's being used in Gaza is imported by the United States
Via Israeli defense contractors to then spy on indigenous reservations across the southwest and the northern borders
So it's like coming from an indigenous perspective
Seeing what was done to my ancestors
via documentation
To my community's ancestors and to countless indigenous communities across America
It's very stark seeing
It happened before our very eyes like seeing what was in textbooks seeing what's in our family history
Happening to other people and has been happening for 75 plus years
So seeing people deny that seeing people actively dismiss it actively sweep it under the rug
Actively side with the pressers and people who are committing genocide against an innocent population
It just it hits a different chord
you know, especially if you and your community and your family have been directly affected by it and
This is precisely why I will always say I will stand with my Palestinian brothers and sisters and
Non-gender-conforming relatives
it's because
The suffering that your family and your communities have been going through for decades
is the same suffering that my community my family and our
Communities have been experiencing for centuries. So the amount of similarities
Bonds us close together the amount of solidarity between our communities
Bonds us close together in our fight to get rid of these colonial oppressors once and for all